要都帶上嗎
Should we pack everything?
我是說 我們打算要待上多久
I mean, how long are we gonna be?
我也不知道要待多久
I don't really know how fucking long but just
不過都帶上吧 速度快點 好嗎
pack everything up and do it as quickly as possible, okay?
傑森
Jason?
都帶上快點
Just pack everything, right now.
好的
Okay.
不會有事的
It's gonna be okay.
好的好的
Okay, okay.
莓果
Berries.
紅莓
Red berries.
好的
Okay.
衛生部門剛剛接到
The department of health has been notified
聯邦緊急事務管理局的通知
by the federal emergency management agency
有一種病毒正大規模感染人群
that a viral infection has severely infected the population.
該病毒感染癥狀包括在腹部或胸部
Symptoms of the virus include a small circular
出現一圈紅疹隨後還會出現
red rash on the abdomen or chest and is followed
噁心 精神錯亂 攻擊性行為
by nausea, delirium and aggressive outbursts
或不可預知的行為
or unpredictable behavior.
如果你或你認識的人出現上述癥狀
If you or anyone you know are exhibiting these symptoms,
請立即聯繫緊急醫療機構
immediately contact emergency medical services.
官員得到的消息認為
Officials have been advised that at this time
此刻一經感染該病毒將立刻對公眾帶來危險
the viral infection poses an immediate danger to the public.
各居民應待在戶內 關上門窗
As a precaution, resident should stay indoors,
以及通風管道以做預防
keep all windows, doors and vents closed.
另外請關閉空調 配給食物
Turn off all air conditioners, ration your--
停下 停車
Stop, stop the car.
傑森 停車
Jason stop the car.
上帝啊 傑森 停車
Christ, Jason, stop the fucking car.
他們有孩子
They have a child.
我們也有
So do we!
知道嗎
Okay?
我們也有
So do we.
你好
Hi there, how are you?
今天天氣很不錯噢
Looks like it's going to be a beautiful day.
你想一起玩嗎
Do you want to play?
我會想你的 希望能盡快見到你
I miss you, hope to see you soon.
一 二 三 四
One, two, three, four.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
操 操
Fuck, fuck!
操
Fuck.
這裏最重要的束西是鋸齒葉
The most important thing here is the saw-tooth leaf.
春天會變成紅色
Turns red during the spring time.
看見了嗎
See that?
好
Okay.
要做一個陷阱 你需要支撐桿 稱重桿和誘餌桿
How to make a deadfall trap, you need a support stick, a weight stick, a bait stick. Okay?
把它們架起來 對好切口 平衡好
And you set them up, notches matching, balance the...
安 你在聽嗎 這非常重要
Ann, are you listening? This is important.
我在聽 但是我不可能寫字跟你講話一樣快
Yes, I can't write as fast as you can fucking talk.
好了
Okay.
別在她面前說髒話
Don't curse in front of her.
好
Fine.
紅莓
Red berries.
紅葉
Red leaves.
不是什麼好兆頭
It's a bad thing.
尤其是在春天
Especially during the spring.
你扣扳機太用力了
You're jerking the trigger.
我擊中了
And I hit it!
那是因為它沒動
That's 'cause it's not moving.
這是把獵槍所以想打死就得打頭或者心臟
It's a rabbit gun, you need to hit head or heart to kill
所以我要你控制呼吸輕輕地
so I need you to control your breathing and lightly--
扣扳機 別太用力 我知道
squeeze, not pull, I know.
我們得節省子彈
We should save our bullets.
你不會打槍再省也白搭
Well, they're of no use if you don't know how to shoot.
還剩多少
How many do we have?
夠多了
Enough.
再來
Do it again.
光靠野果子我們撐不住的
We can't survive on a handful of berries.
我知道
I know.
你妤啊
Hi there, how are you?
今天天氣不錯
Looks like it's going to be a beautiful day.
好吧
Okay.
你好啊
Hi there, how are you?
可惡
Damn it!
操
Fuck!
傑森 怎麼了
Jason, what happened?
不 別碰我
No, don't touch me!
把東西裝車上去
Just get everything in the car.
怎麼了
What happened?
快他媽上車
Just get in the fucking car!
她退燒了嗎
Her fever break?
沒有
No.
傑森 怎麼了
Jason, what happened?
那裏有幾箱子吃的
There were a few boxes of food.
但他們也在那裏
But they were there.
是
Yeah.
他們也在
They were there.
你避開過他們
But you've avoided them before.
這次為什麼突然進攻了
Why did they attack this time?
我不知道
I don't know.
不知道
I don't.
那裏有足夠的食物 足夠的屍體給他們吃
There was enough food to eat there, there was enough bodies.
我以為他們吃完就會走
I thought they would've moved on.
本來都好好的 直到我破開房門的時候
Everything was fine until i cut myself breaking
割傷了自己
into that house.
血流了出來 嚎叫聲就起來了
The blood started flowing and screams grew
他們就涌過來了
and they swarmed.
就好像他們知道
It was like they knew.
他們知道我在流血
They knew I was bleeding.
他們能感覺到
They could sense it.
他們是什麼束西
What are they?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他們和人還有一個共同點
But some part of them is human.
怎麼說
Why is that?
因為他們會死
Because they can die.
拜託 拜託
Come on, come on.
拜託
Come on.
別這樣
Please.
別這樣別這樣
Please, please.
克裏斯
Chris.
他被感染了嗎
Is he infected?
沒有
No.
讓我看一下
Show me.
你叫什麼
Your name?
奧莉維亞
Olivia.
你會幫他嗎
You'll help him?
可以
I can do that.
按住這裏
Press here.
他會沒事的
He'll be okay.
搭把手
Grab an arm.
你們從南邊來的
You coming from the south?
你和你的爸爸
You and your father--
繼父
stepdad.
好吧 差不多
Well, sort of.
克裏斯和我媽媽在一起了 但...
Chris and my mom were, you know, together, but
他們沒有結婚
they never married.
他們本來計劃九月結的 但是…
They planned it for September, but...
你要是想睡車裏也可以
You can sleep in the car if you want.
沒關係的
No, it's fine.
我想睡在他旁邊
I want to sleep near him.
我們會離開的 等他好一點之後
We'll leave, when he's better, I mean.
我們不會賴著你的
We'll leave you alone.
你們為什麼有兩個營地
Why do you have two campsites?
以防我失去一個
In case I lose one or the other.
哦
Oh.
這些有助於掩蓋氣味 把那些扔了
Helps cover your scent, throws them off.
你們要去北邊
You headed north?
是的
Yeah.
你想聽嗎
You wanna hear it?
這就是北方的情況
That's what's up north?
是的
Mm-hmm.
你知道他們在說什麼嗎
Do you know what they're saying?
不知道
No.
所以就是這樣
So that's it.
那邊就是這樣
That's all there is.
克裏斯
Chris?
沒事 莉薇
It's alright, Liv.
沒事的
It's okay.
她說你們正向北方去
She says you're heading north.
是啊 好歹試一下
Yeah, trying to at least.
我們聽說那裏疫情已經被控制了
We hear it's in check up there.
誰特麼知道
Who the fuck knows, right?
你這設置的很好
You have a pretty nice setup here.
很多人拼了命都想擁有這些
Most people would kill for this stuff.
你有帳篷
You gotta tent.
食物 就我來看
Food, from what I can tell.
還有車
Car.
你的油箱是滿的嗎 -不是
You gotta full tank? - No.
只是個能躲雨的地方
Just a place to hide from the rain.
哦
Ugh.
謝謝
Thank you.
為了你為我倆所做的一切
For what you did, for both of us.
現在沒什麼人會這麼做了
Not a lot of people would do that nowadays.
我們明早就出發
We'll be gone in the morning.
好的
Okay.
起來了孩子 出發了
Get up, kiddo, let's go.
進帳篷裏去
Let's get in the tent.
快點進去
Come on, get in!
所以你們在外面呆多久了
So, how long you been out here?
自爆發開始的時候
Since it started.
嗯
Hmm.
你為什麼要來這人煙稀少的地方
Why you all the way out here in the middle of nowhere?
我丈夫自小在這樹林裏長大的
My husband grew up in these woods.
他住在從這往西一公里多的小鎮上
He lived in a town a mile or two west.
他把我們帶來這裏
He brought us out here.
他覺得這裏最安全
It's where he felt safest.
是他教你如何成為林中高手的嗎
Is that who taught you how to be woods woman-y?
他將畢生所學都教給了我
He taught me what he could.
怎麼了
What?
行了 莉薇
Come on, Liv.
我們一直聽到有流言
We kept hearing things, you know.
為什麼費城一天就淪陷 而一些窮鄉僻壤
How Philly went down in a day but some backwater,
像貝瑟爾一個月都沒受到攻擊
berg like bethel didn't get hit for a month.
所以莉薇的母親蘇珊娜說"我們等著"
So Suzanne, Liv's mom, she said, "let's wait."
就他媽等著
Let's just fucking wait.
她甚至還覺得紅十字會
She even thought that the red cross was handing out
在急著去發放解藥
the cure in bottles over in trout run.
結果發現他們只發了熱巧克力
Turns out they were just handing out hot chocolate
和芝士三明治
and cheese sandwiches.
沒過多久蘇珊腹部出現小傷口
And then Suzy got some sores on her belly,
就像一個個小圓圈
they just looked like little circles.
你知道嗎
You know?
小跳蚤咬的
Little flea bites.
但情況開始惡化了
And then they started getting worse.
傷口開始流血化膿
Started bleeding and giving off some sort of white puss.
兩天之後 她攻擊了莉薇
Two days later, she, she attacked Liv.
她試圖徒手撕開她
She tried to rip her apart with her bare hands.
也就是那個時候我把她綁在床上
So that's when I tied her to the bed.
她就只會吼叫
And all she did was scream.
我們把她在那綁了幾天
We left her there for a few days.
就只是聽她一直叫
Just listening to her scream.
你就不管她了
You just left her?
綁在床上
Tied to the bed?
某種程度上
In a way,
是的
yeah.
我從廚房拿了把刀
I took a kitchen knife and,
從她耳朵紮了進去
shoved it in her ear.
我一直推一直推
And I kept on pushing and pushing.
直到她不再吼叫
Until the screams stopped.
我覺得她會原諒我
I like to think that she forgave me, though.
她聽到我說對不起了而且信以為真
That she heard me say I'm sorry and believed it.
我的天哪 不要
Oh, my god, oh my god, no!
快跳下去
Come on, you're going in!
我們走
Here we go!
洗澡時間到
Bath time.
怎麼了 我還沒把你扔進去呢 我的天
What, I didn't even throw you in. Oh my god.
這水都沒有那麼涼
These waters aren't even that cold.
-天哪 -看多棒
- Oh man. - See, it's nice.
看起來真糟糕
It looks awful.
我不放心你在我身後 你走遠點
I don't trust you behind me, get out of here.
我可以推你一把
Well, I can push you.
老天 這裏有魚嗎
God, are there even any fish here?
湖邊都這樣 莉薇
Law of the lake, Liv.
有漁夫的地方就沒有魚了
Where there are fishermen, there are no fish.
對 但這是河啊
Yeah, but we're on a river.
一樣的道理
Rules still apply.
我和馬特·泰爾一起捕過魚
I went on this fishing trip once with Matt theil.
你還記得馬特嗎 莉薇
You remember Matt, Liv?
壯的像頭牛的那個
Guy was built like a fucking tank.
他能用牙齒起開啤酒瓶
He could open bottles of beer with his teeth.
整天宅著玩《使命召喚》
Use to play call of duty 24/7.
反正 有一次馬特租了條船
Anyway, Matt rented a boat one time, well, it wasn't really
好吧也稱不上是船 頂多就是艘小破艇
a boat, it was more of a skiff.
小到甚至都包不住裏面的燈光
Tiny one at that, couldn't even fit a case of fucking natty light in it.
別說了
Stop.
你說哈
What?
別說了
Just stop.
行吧
Okay.
前面在河邊你幹嘛不讓我說話了
Hey, why did you stop me earlier at the river?
我就是覺得有的時候
You know sometimes you,
你好像忘了現實是什麼慘樣
it feels like you forget what's out there.
反正就是前一秒你還在說
I don't know, one minute you're telling me about
你怎麼把你老婆殺了
how you killed your wife.
下一秒你就讓我覺得
And the next, it's just like,
我們好像只是外出野營
we're on a weekend camping trip.
過了週末一切就恢復正常
We'll all return to normalcy on Monday.
你老婆身上長的那些小傷口
You know those rings your wife had?
我早在之前就已經見識過了
We saw them before anyone knew what was going on.
我們給急診室的病人們擠膿血
We get patients in the er oozing puss and blood.
傷口就在不斷腐化周圍的皮膚
The rings just devouring the skin around it.
不斷地寄生擴散腐爛
Feeding on it like it knew what it was gonna become.
他們還能躺在床士的唯一原因
The only thing keeping them down there
就是傷口還沒有完全吞噬遍佈整個身子
is the fact that they haven't eaten all the bodies yet.
所有像你老婆那樣被感染的人
You know, all those people like your wife,
只能被綁在床上沒人再管
just left and tied to the bed.
我做不到
I can't.
我沒辦法忘記這些畫面
I can't just choose to forget that.
我沒有忘記
I didn't forget.
我只是挑了好的回憶然後適時地去回想
I just choose what to remember and when to remember it.
去睡覺吧
Get some sleep, alright?
已經被掃蕩過了 我只能找到這麼點
They took two houses before I found the last amount.
得想辦法讓海莉退燒
Hailey needs something to bring her fever down.
我們還得要食物
And we need food.
你不能就這麼走
You can't just quit.
你把我們救了出來 傑森
You brought us out here for a reason, Jason.
你可以選擇不救
This was your call.
我們得救了
And we survived.
我們活下來了
We've gotten by.
得過且過可不算
Getting by isn't life.
可我們現在只能得過且過了
Getting by is all we have left.
你得走了
You need to go.
嗯
Yeah.
泥巴有用嗎
Will this mud work?
不知道
I don't know.
應該能擋掉點氣味
Should mask the scent.
好
Right.
天啊
Gosh.
對不起
I'm sorry.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
我們絕不只是得過且過
We're not just getting by.
我們還不到那麼絕望
We have more left than you think.
好
Okay.
你看到她了嗎
You seen her?
沒
Nah-uh.
我們什麼時候走
When are we leaving?
過會兒
Soon.
你總是說我們要不斷前進
You always say we have to keep moving.
停下來的人只有死
Those who stay, die.
我們會走的 只是再等一會
We'll keep going, just not yet.
怎麼我們留在這是因為她
So what, we're staying because of her?
不是 我們留在這是因為她能弄到食物
No, we're staying because she has access to food
和水
and water.
我們該感恩了 麗薇
We should be thankful, Liv.
為什麼我們離開會有影響
Why does it matter if we're leaving anyway?
確實有影響
Well, it does matter.
這是她應得的
She deserves it.
-天知道她經歷了些什麼 -是 但我們也經歷了...
- Lord knows what she's been through. - Yeah but we've been through--
是的 我們也一路坎坷 麗薇
we'll, we've all been through shit, Liv.
但至少我們有彼此
But at least you and i had each other.
她孤苦伶仃
She didn't have anybody.
媽的
Shit.
給你
Here.
沒事 沒事 我看看
I'm fine, I'm fine. Let me see.
不用了
No, it's fine.
讓我看看
Let me see.
你為什麼還戴著這個
Why do you still wear it?
大概是習慣了
Habit, I guess.
我以前很喜歡看這個節目
I use to love that show.
我女兒喜歡彩色的
My daughter loved the colorful ones.
他們怎麼了
What happened to them?
我是說你的家人
Your family, I mean.
和大家的遭遇一樣
Same thing that happened to everyone elses.
你在分配食物
You're rationing.
是的
Yeah.
路上總是找不到吃的
Can't always find food on the road.
你要走了
You're leaving, then.
是的 馬上
Yeah, soon.
你可以多拿一點 如果…
You can take more if--
不用了 真的不用了
nah, nah, please.
我們帶走的食物越多 就越需要你到那裏去搞食物
The more food we take, the more you have to go down there and get some.
要不你和我們一起走吧
Hey, why don't you come with us?
為什麼不
Why not?
你怎麼知道離開這裏會比留在這兒好
How do you know if what's out there is any better than what's here?
確實不知道 但是這個地方是能當暫時的避難天堂
Yes we don't really. But, I mean, this place can only be paradise for so long.
這裏並不是天堂
It's not a paradise.
你有麗薇了 所以你得找個地方生存下來
You've got Liv so you need to find a place to survive.
我覺得你應該向北去
For you, it's north.
而我應該留在這裏
For me, it's here.
如果我在這裏打中那顆樹你要給我什麼
Hey, what would you give me if I hit that tree right there?
怎麼你還是五歲小孩嗎 我十二歲 非常感謝
What are you, like five? I am 12, thank you very much.
說真的你要給我什麼
Seriously, what are you gonna give me?
那邊的那稞樹
That tree right there.
呃
Um.
我給你做晚飯
I'll cook you dinner.
晚飯 有沒搞錯
Dinner, really?
每晚都是你為我們做晚飯
You cook us dinner every night.
再說一句那稞樹可是在45米開外哦
Plus that tree's 50 yards away.
45米
50 yards?
最多27米
Uh 30, tops.
好吧 行
Alright, fine.
你要給我什麼
Still, what are you gonna give me?
好吧
Fine.
我們不定量了
We won't ration.
天啊 你一定要打中
My god, you have to.
你一定要打中
You have to!
從這裏開始可以嗎
So from here, is this okay?
是的 你必須特別准才行
Yeah and you have to make precisely that,
你看見那下面的洞了嗎
you see that little hole at the bottom there?
中間的那個
The one right in the middle.
是的
Yeah.
那個
That.
好吧
Alright.
你給我什麼
What are you gonna give me?
晚飯之類的
The dinner thing.
那不行 那是安的
You can't have that thing, that's Ann's thing.
但是我們除了四塊餅乾以外能吃 沒別的了
Yeah but we get to eat more than four fucking crackers.
好吧 你給我什麼呢
Alright, fine then, but what are you gonna give me?
快說
Come on.
我們可以游泳
We can swim.
真的嗎
Really?
真的
Yeah.
你討厭游泳的
You hate swimming.
你竟然討厭游泳
You hate swimming?
不喜歡在湖裏游而己
Just in lakes.
我不喜歡看不到底
I don't like not seeing the bottom.
好了
Alright.
就這個 就拿它當彈珠了
This right here, it's for all the marbles.
行了 扔一個看看
Okay, come one.
是大餐還是游泳
Big ol' dinner and swim time.
拭目以待
Alright? Here we go.
等等不不我手滑了
Oh wait, no, no, I slipped.
不行不行 剛才是個錯誤的開始
Oh, nope, nope. That was a false start.
讓我再扔一次 再扔一次
Give me one more shot, i get a second shot.
看著
Come on, now.
天啊 有什麼束西碰我的腳了
Oh my god, something just touched my foot.
又碰了一下
Did it again.
幹嘛
What?
沒事
Nothing.
沒什麼事
It's not nothing.
沒事
It's nothing.
就是沒事
Yeah, it's nothing.
哦喲 對不起
Oops, sorry.
一會兒見
See you later.
從沒想過我會懷念這個鬼東西
Mmm. Never thought I'd miss this shit.
想讓我給你做一個嗎
Oh, you want me to make you one?
我挺擅長的
I'm really good.
我試試
Let me try.
開始
There we go.
來點甜菜
Little beet.
來點橄欖
Little olive.
給你
There you go.
好吃吧
It's good, right?
要不要來點芝士
Need more cheese, though?
給
Here.
來呀
Come on.
來點芝士吧 莉薇
Want some cheese, Liv?
她看起來像媽媽
She looks like mom.
頭髮不太像
I mean, not the hair but.
她挺擅長野外生存的
She's good at this stuff, you know?
如果是我的話 我心裏也會啊的一聲
I mean, if it was me, i would just be like, ah!
那就是你想讓她跟我們一起走的原因嗎
Is that why you want her to come with us?
因為她很擅長這類事情嗎
I mean, 'cause she's good at this kind of thing?
如果那天她沒發現我們的話 我們會怎樣
Now, where would we be if she didn't find us that day?
我會死掉 你會孤身一人
I'd be dead and you'd be alone.
沒有人該受這種罪
Nobody deserves that.
不應該是你 也不應該是她
Not you, not her.
我想讓她來是因為你
I want her to come because of you.
因為她能照顧好我們
Because she takes good care of us.
因為我也想照顧她
Because I wanna take care of her, too.
我能戴戴嗎
Can I try that on?
可以
Sure.
他怎麼向你求婚的
How did he ask you?
說來話長
Well.
某個週五我發現自己懷孕了
I found out I was pregnant on a Friday.
告訴他時已經很晚了
It was late and I told him.
他看了我一眼就走了
And he just looked at me and he left.
午夜時他滿身酒氣地回來了
At midnight, he came back, smelling like liquor
就坐在床沿上
and he just sat down at the edge of the bed
拿著枚戒指給我看
and showed me a ring.
他沒開口我就同意了
He didn't asked me, but I said yes.
然後我們就睡了
And then we went to bed.
戒指應該是從當鋪搞來的
I think it came from a pawnshop.
我並不是特別介意
Part of me didn't care.
我莫名覺得那是這一切發生的唯一途徑
Somehow I knew that was the only way it would happen.
克裏斯帶我媽去了毛伊島
Chris took my mom to Maui.
日落時他在沙灘上向她求了婚
He asked her on the beach during a sunset.
她說那是她一生中最幸福的時刻
She said it was the best day of her life.
真好看
It's nice.
是的
It is.
想到你的束西以前是別人的
Sorta weird to think it was someone else's
多少會有點膈應
before it was yours.
就這樣
Yes.
好了
Okay.
我去去就回
I'll be back.
媽媽愛你 知道嗎
Mama loves you, okay?
好啦 你知道的 對嗎
Alright, you know that?
你知道我多愛你 對嗎
You know how much I love you?
再見 寶貝閨女
Bye, baby girl.
再見 甜心
Bye, sweetness.
好了
Okay.
媽媽在這兒
Shh, mama's here.
丟下你真是對不起
I'm so sorry I left you.
真對不起
I'm so sorry.
對不起
我一點也不瞭解你
Y'know, I don't know anything about you
除了你明顯很固執
other than the fact that you'restubborn.
我不固執
I'm not stubborn. Aha!
只有固執的人會立馬否認自己固執
Only stubborn people instantly deny being stubborn.
你這叫套路
It's called entrapment.
也許吧
Maybe.
但是我們現在知道了你  毫無疑問 安 不管你到底姓什麼
But now we know beyond a shadow of a doubt that you, Ann, whatever the hell your last name is,
都很固執
is stubborn.
你很精於此道
You're good at that.
精於什麼
What exactly?
讓我忘了自己為什麼在這兒
Making me forget why I'm here.
晚安 克裏斯
Goodnight, Chris.
晚安
Goodnight.
跟我們走吧
Come with us.
這事說過了
We've talked about this.
一切皆可改變
Things can change.
安娜貝拉·羅斯·馬歇爾
Annabelle rose Marshall.
器官捐獻者
Organ donor.
你真行
Good for you.
留下吧
Stay.
就留在這兒吧
Stay right here.
別走了
Stay.
不 不行
No. We can't.
那些留在原處的 都死在這兒了
Those that stay put, die here.
我還活著呢
Well, I'm alive.
話是沒錯 但看看你一家子的下場
Yeah, but look what happened to your family.
安 我不是故意的
Ann, I didn't mean it.
安 真的對不起 我不是…
Ann, I'm so sorry, I didn't--
她肯定吃掉了一些
she must've taken some.
本來還有至少一盒子餅乾的
I mean, there was at least a box of crackers--
噢 操 奧莉維亞
Oh fuck! Olivia!
克裏斯
Chris!
克裏斯 等等
Chris, wait!
奧莉維亞
Olivia!
莉薇 你在哪兒
Liv, where are you?
奧莉維亞
Olivia!
你吃到嘴裏去了嗎
Did you get any in your mouth?
莉薇
Liv?
沒有
No.
你呢
You?
沒 應該沒有
No, I don't think so.
你本有可能會吃到的
You would've tasted it.
那個東西到這兒來了
That thing that came up here.
沒有
They didn't.
一定是食物太稀缺了
Food must be scarce.
你還是想留下來嗎
You still wanna stay.
我們明天一早就出發
We're leaving in the morning.
你怎麼樣啊 小美人
How are you, pretty girl?
你看到什麼了啊
What do you see?
你看到什麼了
你喜歡和媽媽待在一起嗎
Yes, you like being with your mama?
很好 很好 我們要走啦
Yes, yes, here we go.
噢 海莉
Oh, Hailey.
過來 寶寶
Come here, my love.
我們走了 我們走了
Here we go, here we go.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
克裏斯
Chris.
克裏斯 停下
Chris, stop.
你為什麼不和我們一起
Why won't you come with us?
因為
Because,
我 我還沒有準備好
I'm, I'm not ready.
你他媽的會死在這裏的
You're gonna fucking die here!
也許我就他媽的應該死在這裏
Well, maybe I deserve to fucking die here.
哦 原來是這麼回事
Oh, so that's what this is.
你把這當作是某種懲罰
This is some sorta punishment.
不管你曾做過些什麼 別管他媽的贖罪了
Fucking atone for whatever it is you did
趕緊翻篇上路吧
and move on, already.
這個世界不是你說了饒恕了之後
This isn't a world where you can just forgive
就能向前看的
and move on.
我們過去搞砸了事情之後會承認錯誤
We use to be able to fuck up and then say you're sorry
然而一旦自我感覺良好後又會重蹈覆轍
and feel better until the next time you fuck up.
有了女兒之後我不會再犯下一次了
With my daughter, there was no next time.
所以我能向誰道歉
So who can I apologize to?
哈 克裏斯
Huh, Chris?
這裏已經沒有人了
There's no one here.
我的妻子
Yeah well, my wife,
她也不在這
she isn't here either.
我在她女兒面前親手把她媽殺了
I fucking killed her in front of her daughter.
她曾經是不是他們中的一員不重要
And it doesn't matter if she was one of them or not,
我都面對過
I confronted it.
我不怪自己 不怪她 都是他們的錯
And I don't blame me, I don't blame her, I blame them.
那個不正常的世界 安 是你自己的
The only world that won't right itself, Ann, is your own.
不正常的原因也是因為你
And the reason for that is because of you.
跟這裏發生的一切無關 跟北邊也無關 只跟你有關
Not because of what happened here or what's north, you.
你的家人他們都不在這裏了
Look, your family, they aren't here anymore,
但是你還在
but you are.
所以求你了 直面遺憾 接受現實
So please, just tell yourself you're sorry, accept it
走出陰霾 繼續前行
and move the fuck on, already.
我們需要更多的食物
We're gonna need more food.
我自己忙不過來
And I won't be able to get it by myself.
那你告訴我讓我干哈
You just tell me what to do.
我也來
I'm coming, too.
莉薇 你不用來
Liv, no your not.
算我一個
I'm coming!
我和安還有其他人一樣可以幫上忙
I'm just the same as Ann or anyone else, I can help.
眾人拾柴火焰高
Three carrying food is better than two.
好吧
Fine.
克裏斯會引開它們
Chris will distract them.
我們要做的就是
All you and I will do is fill our packs
盡可能的裝滿行囊
with everything you can.
只要食物 別的不要
Just food, nothing else.
然後撒腿就跑
And then we run.
看到它們你就跑 不用管我
First sign of them, you run, don't worry about me.
懂了嗎 莉薇
Okay, Liv?
莉薇 你還好嗎
Liv, you okay?
我還好
Yeah, I'm fine.
好的
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
我們都不會有事的
Look, we're all gonna be fine.
克裏斯會沒事的
Chris, Chris is gonna be fine.
我知道
I know.
我知道他不會有事的
I know he's gonna be fine.
該我們了 走吧
That's us. Let's go.
有什麼食物就拿什麼
Grab any food you can find.
莉薇 加快速度
Liv, we gotta be quick!
有什麼拿什麼
Just grab any food you can.
奧利維亞 怎麼了
Olivia, what the hell?
我們要走了
We gotta go.
你們他媽
What are you...
我們得...
We have to, we have to...
We have to--
我以為會出更多的血呢
Thought it would bleed more.
不
No!
別
Don't! Liv!
怎麼了 它們在追我
What's wrong? They're after me,
安呢
where's Ann?
它們沒有
No, they're not.
我甩開了它們
I lost them.
安呢
Where's Ann?
她
She--
安呢
where's Ann?
她
She's...
哦 他媽的
Oh fuck!
快回車裏
Get in the car.
-克裏斯 我... -回他媽的車裏
- Chris, I-- - Get in the fucking car!
奧利維亞
Olivia!
好吧
Okay.